A Guide to the Howell for Governor Campaign financial records, 1972-1973
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Howell for Governor Campaign financial records, 1972-1973
The Library of Virginia
28024
.675 cu. ft. and 2 boxes
Howell for Governor Campaign
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Henry E. Howell, Jr., Norfolk and Richmond, Virginia.
Custodial History
Accessions 28083, 28129, and 28180 are filed with accession 28024.
Historical Information
Henry E. Howell (1920-1997) was the Democratic nominee for governor of Virginia in 1973. He lost an extremely close race to Republican Mills Godwin (1914-1999).
Scope and Content
Financial records, 1972-1973, of the Howell for Governor Campaign consisting of disclosures of all contributions to and disbursements by the campaign for Henry E. Howell (1920-1997), Democratic candidate for governor of Virginia. Reports are from both the statewide campaign and local organizations supporting Howell. Papers also include Howell's personal financial records consisting of income tax returns, life insurance policies, and stock certificates.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Disclosure of all Contributions and Disbursements, 1972-1973
Series II: Personal Financial Papers
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Howell for Governor, 1977 campaign financial disclosures, 1975-1977 (LVA accession 29469)
Mills E. Godwin for Governor Campaign reports of campaign contributions and expenditures, 1973-1974 (LVA accession 28165).
Contents List
- Series I: Disclosure of all Contributions and Disbursements, 1972-1973., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 1-2)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 31 July 1972-28 June 1973, copy 1. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 31 July 1972-28 June 1973, copy 2. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 29 June-20 August 1973, original (statewide). (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 29 June-20 August 1973, original (local organizations). (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 29 June-20 August 1973, desk copy 1 (statewide and local). (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 29 June-20 August 1973, desk copy 2 (statewide and local). (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 23 October 1973 (statewide). (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 23 October 1973 (local). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, financial committee supplement, 23 October 1973. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 2 November 1973-Danville. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 20 November 1973-Peninsula. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 21 November 1973-Front Royal. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 30 November 1973-Gloucester. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 30 November 1973-Hopewell. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 30 November 1973-Woodstock. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 30 November 1973-Concerned Citizens for Howell. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 1 December 1973-Charlottesville. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 1 December 1973-Montgomery County. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 1 December 1973-Petersburg. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 3 December 1973-Chesapeake. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 3 December 1973-Fredericksburg. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 3 December 1973-Halifax. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 3 December 1973-Martinsville. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 3 December 1973-Norfolk. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 3 December 1973-Portsmouth. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 3 December 1973-Prince William. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 3 December 1973-Staunton. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 3 December 1973-Suffolk. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 4 December 1973-Northern Virginia. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 4 December 1973-Richmond. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Disclosure of all contributions and disbursements, 5 December 1973-statewide. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Series II: Personal Financial Papers., Extent: 1 box. (Box 2)
  - Personal income tax, 1968. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Personal income tax, 1969. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Personal income tax, 1970. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Personal income tax, 1971. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Personal income tax, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Life insurance policies. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Stock certificates. (Box 2, Folder 31)